Rafael Silveira

Web developer

João Jacob Bainy, 201, 96065-340, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul Brazil

in

I have a degree in Computer Engineering from the Federal University of Pelotas – UFPel and medium and technical (Electromechanical) from IFSul. During college, I worked with Scientific Initiation and Tutorial Education Program (PET) for three years, where I also worked in the areas of Research, Extension and Teaching winning awards as: Innovative Ideas Competition UFPel and highlighted in the session of Exact Sciences of Scientific UFPel Initiation Congress (CIC). I also have experience in the field of automation involving radio frequency identification systems (RFID). In my free time, I usually study new technologies and develop projects involving electronics with web development integration.

SKILLS

Development

Master

html | css | javascript | php | nodejs |

wordpress | symfony framework |

laravel framework | silex micro-framework |

docker | linux | shellscript

Hardware

Master

arduino | raspberrypi

WORK EXPERIENCE

Back-end Developer at POSSIBLE BRAZIL November 2015- Current

http://possible.com

I worked with technologies such as PHP, NodeJS, HTML 5, MySQL and MongoDB. I also had experience using Symfony, Sllex, Node-Red, CakePHP, Laravel, WordPress (CMS) frameworks and Agile Methodology.

 Created the Possible Maker Space at POSSIBLE Brazil office, a place where It's possible to develop products involving free hardware such as Arduino and Raspberry Pi.

Developer at Hut8 March 2014- October 2015

http://www.hut8.com.br

I worked with mobile development for Android platforms. I helped to develop the first mobile app of the Federal University of Pelotas – UFPel.

EDUCATION

Graduation Project Management and Business Intelligence at SENAC

2016 - 2017

Bachelor Computer Engineer at University of Pelotas

2011 - 2015
Technical ELETROMECHANICAL at IFSUL 2007 - 2008
AWARDS
Highlight in the session of Exact Sciences at CIC UFPEL 2015
Paper entitled "Development of a solution for the record of attendance an access control on academic events using identification and communication by radio frequency". Developed with Group of Architectures and Integrated Circuits – GACI UFPel
Innovative Ideas Competition at UFPEL 2013
Paper entitled "Tracing system for collective transport vehicles using technology Arduino".
PUBLICATIONS
Development of a solution for the record of attendance an access control on academic events using identification and communication by radio frequency in UFSM 1 October 2016
Tracing system for collective transport vehicles using technology Arduino in UFPel 1 April 2013

Portuguese Native speaker

LANGUAGES

English Advanced